<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Documentation on AsCode - Terraform Alternative Syntax</title><link>https://ascode.run/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Documentation on AsCode - Terraform Alternative Syntax</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ascode.run/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Quick Install</title><link>https://ascode.run/docs/install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ascode.run/docs/install/</guid><description>AsCode is written in Go with support for multiple platforms.
The latest release can be found at GitHub Releases., currently provides pre-built binaries for the following:
Linux macOS (Darwin) Windows Binary (Cross-platform) Download the appropriate version for your platform from GitHub Releases.. Once downloaded, the binary can be run from anywhere. You don’t need to install it into a global location.
Ideally, you should install it somewhere in your PATH for easy use.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://ascode.run/docs/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ascode.run/docs/getting-started/</guid><description>This page explains the basics of using AsCode to define your infrastructure in Terraform. It assumes that you have already installed the Ascode.
&amp;gt; ascode --help Usage: ascode [OPTIONS] &amp;lt;repl | run | version&amp;gt; AsCode - Terraform Alternative Syntax. Help Options: -h, --help Show this help message Available commands: repl Run as interactive shell. run Run parses, resolves, and executes a Starlark file. version Version prints information about this binary. The repl command The repl command provides a handy REPL interface for debugging and tinkering with AsCode.</description></item><item><title>GitHub Action</title><link>https://ascode.run/docs/github-action/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ascode.run/docs/github-action/</guid><description>TODO</description></item><item><title/><link>https://ascode.run/docs/_home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ascode.run/docs/_home/</guid><description>AsCode allows you to describe your infrastructure using an expressive language in Terraform without writing a single line of HCL.</description></item></channel></rss>